[Music]
stop it
yeah let's see oh we got one person yeah
welcome to four look at this oh do we
not we're not posting on Twitter there
we go
should be hello shared on Twitter
can we go there we go okay so we've got
61 people Wow 61 people all right so
these this periscope is to get the world
know our port to a new car which is a
Subaru yeah nobody would have I mean
like I guess buddy would have expected
that cannot see because the new GF is
hidden under the trim which is why the
new GF is actually great so this is like
a first car that we ported using
something that does not require you to
permanently remove dreams from your car
and so you can put back your dreams it
would be very bad especially like for a
super or having to remove the dreams
because all these piece is like a single
trim so and there is not much space
underneath so the really the only
solution is developing something very
tiny and I just shuffle it in there and
it's working great so some things it
doesn't have any any switch so all this
which are controlled so the stock and
non stock is control to the Panda
so we repor pizzelle can and can control
relay and the relay decides if passing
through the stock system or actually
passing through open pilot so when panda
sees ten messages like ten messages that
open pilot wants to send to the car then
it automatically open the relay
and you disconnect the camera from the
rest of the canvas of the car and then
you can you can decide what to forward
and walk to a place so people can
actually water again so what else can we
say about is there any question see I
missed a lot of questions okay
where's Jorge yep let's see let's see
no it's not it's not your giraffe we we
built our own let's see yeah no radar
everything's done with the cameras so
yeah let alone implementation of open
pilots because there is no operator in
this car we can't use the red so we let
the camera the eyesight system still do
the longitudinal controller and we just
take control of the data value it's
similar to what we do with other cars
like you and I drew says how some other
in San Diego oh well you don't come to
San Francisco very often true this is
the San Francisco we still have to move
yeah we're gonna be moving through soon
can't wait actually a good day today see
it's this 0.6 no no it's not zero six
six is we're gonna release its own is
5.11
see any other questions Oh gia frog see
it was a super heart well great the head
is aprox with you see oh yeah we did
bring we did bring some giraffe to show
off oh yeah so this piece up here which
has the Panda this so you have the obd2
rj45 and you have a 10 pin connector and
then you have what's actually doing all
the work
he's got a relay yeah yeah do a nice
water through yeah it's great beef ten
pen 26 pin which is you're gonna be your
car harness and that connects to the
camera this is just a prototype one the
other ones look a lot better yeah I mean
what has you do skies every day yeah the
relay which controls everything the 17
is what like go connects to your pan
announces it is on your car to 10 10
cozy Spears up to the Panda up to the
giraffe yes camera cover and the 2016 is
the single pin connect to do the single
connector that like connects the car to
the camera yep so if you lose if you
lose connection it'll actually switch
back to stock automatically yeah I mean
we can test it basically yeah what
happens is like if open pile of stops
working or get disconnected after five
seconds the relay will automatically
close so if for example you connect the
yin or the enforce whatever reason stops
sending canned messages the car will
fault because you stopped sending
messages and then after five seconds you
will the relay will actually close and
you go back to stock of course you're
gonna still have some faults in the car
but the idea is that when the car is off
you can disconnect your own and that's
the very simplest way to be back stock
yeah so the relay will not open if open
pilot is not sending Cal messages yeah
yeah
so okay how's the torque the torque I
would say is definitely better than they
wound up it's probably a little lower
than the Toyota there is a huge lag in
controlling in actuator controls so if
proof of weather is familiar weight of a
pilot code there is power there is one
piece in the code where we are called a
leg doctor it looks like and that's set
2.4 seconds for four for the Subaru
which is a lot but it seems to be
working pretty well so that's fine
and yes talk level talk level is descent
I would say stock ACC isn't too bad the
problem is that now we're stopped and
the car is gonna disabled so you can't
do stopping though it can bring you to
stop but then it will auto disable the
car I like is you see after three
seconds that you're stopped somewhat
annoying I believe the reason why they
do that is because this car is like a
handbrake so it doesn't have the
electronic part brake and so if you
don't have a tronic back brake and
you're stopped and something bad happens
and you want to be able to lock the car
and to block the car and have the car
standing still and so if you have an APB
you can do that if you have handbrake
you actually can so will this work on
the Impreza 2019 that's what this is any
prison chosen 18 by the way yes so this
port will work with every Subaru that is
on the global platform so pretty much
every new Subaru Impreza's started in
2019 I believe and the some of the 2018
and maybe even 17 outback are on me
somebody who wear the super can correct
me by did all the new Subaru cars are in
this global platform and so this sport
is written for for those cars with minor
modification I believe like a bunch of
people already did it for non global
platform Subaru you can't you can still
use the port so it's still like somewhat
like retroactive on cars that doesn't
have cars that don't have global
platform can still work with this port
so it's not a big deal I think a bunch
of people ready did he turn on the
community yeah so I mean few more things
again about the port I would say
I would say like its pitcher like we
could probably put a bounty if somebody
can find a way to trigger like beeps and
alerts I worked it I don't know like
they only alert and beeps well the only
beep beeping on the car that I could
find was when we turned off ACC so this
double beep these these double beep is a
beep that I can replicate I haven't
found the easy way to do other type of
beeps maybe a repeated chime when there
is somewhat like some important alert to
display or things like that sir if
somebody finds like a good way to send
like an alert with definitely the great
that you know compiled a few guys how do
you like super reverses Honda and Toyota
I would say super always work toward
Anandi the good thing about on the night
deck is that we can do ACC and I would
say OCC is definitely better than the
stock ACC with Subaru you get the stock
ACC which isn't too bad so in terms of a
pilot implementation I would say I would
say it's better than on the parsha the
car itself at least impress I'm not so
impressed this is like understanding
Impreza
is is not an STI is not like the view
that we are see or anything not
suppressed Whitaker well I don't know
people like some people like it's a it's
a full optional character this one it's
like
I wish I wish like eyesight was standard
on an appraiser you need to get like a
high train to get this down there yeah
what's new and five dollar leaven so
it's gonna we're gonna improve like
driver monitoring we're gonna add Subaru
support we are going to strongly reduce
the power consumption of the Panda when
the car is off one of the pain that
people have is of course like all right
if I leave connected the Panda and the
iana for long period when the car is off
we can drain your battery and so we are
working to to actually reduce the power
consumption in idle a lot to give you
like an idea the pond before changes
when it's idle it was consuming about
500 milliwatts and now we cut it by less
than a half so your carry is just
because of the planet the pandas Gannett
is gonna last like several weeks so you
don't have to worry about leaving the
Panda connected
and now you will also have some
improvement on power consumption on day
Monday but we will do more improvement
maybe I probably still within like five
eleven there are still few figures we
need to put you on and so everything
will be reasonable and you will have not
worry about leaving the time that
connected to your car
at least for like several weeks so
mark says we're gonna have another Bay
Area beat up before we all head south
yeah mark will meet up I'll meet up
any more support for auto-tuning maybe
yeah we want to do a better well it
won't be out of uni for a KPI we would
probably encourage try because there is
no reason to out human life you want to
find an optimal tuning for a given car
and then fix your games right so Monty
that we can work on is having a script
that analyzes certain drive well then do
outer tuning life but is now going to be
released for four compile some sort of
gay gonna be like a one-off procedure
that you do is you want to find the
optimal human again for your like
Grossmann control
and I think we're I mean I think Philip
is actually speaking
[Music]
PJ says any consideration for addressing
me on smelling up and break in Oakland
pilot
yes yeah yeah so if my even going 5:39
that's one of the biggest fear yes so
it's gone so originally we talked about
like doing it in a less like okay so
there is an open request they all become
quest is somewhat lazy and it's stop
logging when open vital fits up but I
mean it's not like gonna right now what
happens is when open pilot fills up but
and you don't have any more of them a
bit after without their the Lord care
they'll take the logging process stops
and you are not allowed to engage the
system anymore and that's a big pain so
what we are gonna do is we are still
gonna log but we're gonna add a rotation
right so you stick on lock you're going
to delete all the data and you're still
done a lot like new data and so you can
you can still drive and your stick Aloha
whatever happens like the most recent
events
my brevet yeah we pull the hardware out
again
[Music]
there's the harness
we call this the Panda interphase point
because that's where the Panda actually
attaches up there
the relay and the connectors and
all the pastor stuff on the board here
he said claisen claisen giraffe better
the one we got okay
so I don't know yeah I mean that yeah
there was the other the final rotation
and fixing the oomphel gap was the other
like faulty diamond is a decent merged
in yeah and in our internal branch he
needs some more testing so i don't know
if he was gonna make the calf I got
eleven but we did it just a lot of
testing might be factors will have it
back before the twelve we talked about
being able to update speed limits
what does it mean like update osm oh
like out update on how I am it's like I
don't know how IP are gonna be osm
people 12 like sort of like out of the
procedures like that I don't know no
tonight so the point is like people took
the same compute all the time right so
it's not like people drive like
different routes very often so if
somebody like is doing the same computer
on a daily basis
and on your router you find that in some
spot your speed limit is growing then
you can just fix it and when you're
gonna have it right for for all your
computers right so means like
they ask that people drive are not
randomly distributed across all the US
like rolls it's a given specifically ask
that people keep driving over and over
again for most of the time so we do
believe that if something is missing
from OpenStreetMap it's not a much like
of an issue for any given user to go in
and update it manually that's therefore
why we are very happy to say open
statement because everybody can actually
fix it and update it so we did it I did
it for my copy of
thoughts on side cameras for lane
changing and freeway exits
say
I mean eventually eventually I think
like putting side cameras and more like
at another 60 view is gonna help up but
honestly like we're at the point where
how much more we can do by just like
using a lot better what we have right
now like we're not nearly had to leave
it off using the sensor that we have any
capability the processing that we have
on the yield make sure we could upgrade
the processing jobs to start a process
but we could with more sensors for like
how well are utilizing assessment we
have like ie like a person could almost
perfectly driving I adjusted view that
you would have from the current camera
because you cannot safely they change
but if it happened like side the others
which most of the new cars have totally
fine you can do
there is huge traffic clear back he can
went way too far
differently we go back no no
it's gonna be a long way back oh my god
what happened to George
Pence's around
sometimes I thought Subaru was a bad
topic well it's not banned anymore so
let me look like we were like super oak
was like a pen topic like what a half
year ago because we were literally like
one in a year ago when we said super was
my topic we were supporting how many
cups they were supporting like a few on
thus and we barely started to support to
the office right now turned out that
Subaru is a low-hanging fruit so which
is yummy
it wasn't like that like what I feel
it's not bad anymore
it's just 19
like like literally support like maybe
5560 combination of like car makes car
mother's mother years because possible
provinces as the dildo thing I would say
coming out the way that we were
visioning it back then I mean the deal
intended as like a simulation when your
player L yes not not the way that to be
very beginning now I would say like
we're thinking about better strategy
later yes
but yeah I mean I ran an oscillator
still still still thing
can't go in here yes right yeah yeah
take a look - oh my god
muscle he's got doesn't that through
stopping go so he's gonna be painful
like a compiler needs to be a way to
attention to not like the 0.001 percent
of the people that might be interested
into getting like here and eventually
like ik starting on the pilot but I
would say more like let's make this
product a lot better like we can like we
are like working harder to turn these
into like letting out the sugar trying
product this is this is like use the
father's done and then of course like
making it making it better like
improving features like a lot of more
features that are related to maps we can
do a lot if you know the maps if you
know you can add like a lot of
informations like okay like speed limit
is of course exactly so any place you
can do a lot more you can we already
slowed down for turns but we can do this
pattern we can no stop sign we can no
like traffic all these feelings you know
them if if you do like a matter of
integration and you can argue that I
mean like humans don't use maps to drive
like a human can totally do I find
without knowing where it is and without
knowledge specific features from like a
database but then at the same time we're
not really at the level that like you
can have a machine that rises well as
good as a human we tell normal self and
information we have somewhat like
cheating and getting this information
from from databases so yeah let's make
let's make it a machine a job easier and
let's use as much as many information as
we can from existing databases and like
okay straight Mexican a database
so more magnification more stability
less power consumption more features
definitely like did they actually Trek
open again I'm not sure like how many of
yous like I've listened to Eva masks
interviews with the legs Freedman about
what open pilot is and what buying a
Tesla is what he says like what a game
is if you buy a Taser today you are not
buying a depreciating better asset
you're actually buying an appreciating
asset because the system is gonna get
better over time and I mean I'm not sure
if they like a mother tree that you buy
today he's kind of appreciate over time
because it costs quite a bit of money
stephannie get better over time I'm sure
he's gonna appreciate but I would say
give me the price point of the EON well
maybe yes maybe the you is really like a
depreciating asset like literally
appreciating upset because things that
the yen is capable of doing is gonna get
that a lot of time so
yeah get the neon and get them after she
gets it and then you can recite for more
because we are indeed maybe raising the
price of the yield as the young gets
better this we asked about afford but I
didn't see it for its we tried it we do
really we did release some of the thighs
honestly carol is more like we just
released some of the files that makes
you like the character face like at the
car state
so something that has like like an
understanding of what what the car can
is is saying like it's like all the
castings not like information about the
car
I didn't release the things that allows
open pilot to talk to the car because it
was in a Finnish port but honestly I
don't think it can actually be a Finnish
board because they have this 10 second
timeout after ten second that you
recommended it'll work they force you to
stop commenting the talk for a second I
didn't find that yeah a way to get
around it so let's see this is an
impressive 2018 yeah I mean how many
people are following the 50/50
with all the Subaru haters wasn't you
know they all left
that's why they're not watch as many 8's
I think who serve always a lot of others
yeah people who people have own servers
they continue to buy servers yeah it's a
lot guys so they can cancel the knish
love the car
well the EON be able to handle big
models um yeah I mean if you get smart
how to make Big Brother yes definitely
and definitely like big is somewhat like
the wrong or because we big like big is
not like Anna Jackie that I've been used
for something good but yeah I mean like
a lot better model definitely I was viv
still around of course yeah yeah should
have come but there's in charge the
scopes
my god is so painful like mascara can't
really do something girl you really need
to get like a cab with EPP you and I
have like toasted ago
well actually I think there is a way to
cheat like to make this car like having
for stopping though you probably have to
spam something and just outside the
counter can be portable compiled except
for requests right yeah
find it fine you can fix it yep we about
I definitely put up about if some people
can find like way to come to take care
more times than just like this one this
was the only time that I found any
trucks
besides the ridgeline
hi the only one I fit that common we
looked into it it doesn't add Lane keep
assist like you can't you can't come and
laying keep you can cook it doesn't have
like thank you it just has a word yes so
it's gonna go baby yeah this channel
what about the Shannon Sienna Englishman
yeah many bad
all right
they love the traffic scopes oh my god
well I mean any other questions guys
so if you have Subaru you can yeah we'll
put it up on the shop going on the shop
and it'll people open-source it - yeah
we always do
yes definitely every gif is open then
I'll get a push to github when start
selling yeah
cool okay that's it guys been a pleasure
all right guys take care have fun all
right right